/**
 * quizes.js
 *
 * @author Philip Van Raalte
 * @date 2017-11-09
 */
import {unlockCapcom, unlockKonami, unlockNintendo, unlockSega, unlockSNK, unlockSquareSoft} from './ng/UnlockMedals';

export default [
  {
    name: "Sega Trivia",
    uniqueID: "sega",
    colour: "#011AB2",
    unlock: unlockSega,
    questions: [
      {question: "When was Sega founded?", answers: ["1960", "1978", "1889", "1980"], correct: 0},
      {question: "When was the SG-1000 released in Japan?", answers: ["1976", "1983", "1985", "1982"], correct: 1},
      {question: "What is the sequel to Zaxxon?", answers: ["Zaxxon 2", "Zaxxon II", "Super Zaxxon", "Zaxxon 2000"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When was the Master System released in Europe", answers: ["1985", "1987", "1986", "1988"], correct: 1},
      {question: "What was the Master System called in Japan?", answers: ["Super SG", "Sega Mark III", "Sega Entertainment System", "SG-2500"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Which of the following was a launch game for the Master System in the US?", answers: ["R-Type", "Galaga", "Hang-On", "Wonder Boy"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Who is the designer of Out Run?", answers: ["David Rosen", "Naoto Ohshima", "Hitoshi Yamagami", "Yu Suzuki"], correct: 3},
      {question: "How many stages does Fantasy Zone have?", answers: ["8", "20", "5", "10"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Who is the antagonist in Alex Kidd in Miracle World?", answers: ["Nurari", "Prince Egle", "Niban", "Janken"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Where does Golden Axe take place?", answers: ["Adder", "Yuria", "Kemonanji", "Miracle World"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When was the Sega Genesis released in North America?", answers: ["1991", "1987", "1989", "1990"], correct: 2},
      {question: "How many units of the Genesis did Sega aim to sell in its first year?", answers: ["1,000,000", "500,000", "250,000", "2,000,000"], correct: 0},
      {question: "What genre did Katz think was the key to winning the American audience?", answers: ["Platformer", "Racing", "Sports", "Shooter"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Which game was designed to be a \"Mario-killer\"?", answers: ["Sonic the Hedgehog", "Ecco the Dolphin", "Ristar", "Shinobi"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Who was the director of The Revenge of Shinobi?", answers: ["Noriyoshi Ohba", "Yu Suzuki", "Hirokazu Yasuhara", "Naoto Ohshima"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Who is the antagonist in Sonic the Hedgehog?", answers: ["Mr. Eggman", "Tails", "Dr. Ivo Robotnik", "Janken"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Sonic the Hedgehog composer, Masato Nakamura, was the bassist of which band?", answers: ["Arashi", "Dreams Come True", "Do As Infinity", "Zard"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When was the Game Gear released in Europe?", answers: ["1993", "1990", "1991", "1995"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Which of the following was not a launch game for the Game Gear in the US?", answers: ["Revenge of Drancon", "Psychic World", "Columns", "Sonic Chaos"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Kalinske tried to make a deal with Silicon Graphics for a graphics chip. Who rejected the proposal?", answers: ["Sega of Japan", "Sega of America", "Silicon Graphics", "Sony"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Which game was cancelled?", answers: ["Super Sonic 3D", "Golden Axe III", "Sonic X-treme", "Shinobi V"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When was the Dreamcast released in Europe?", answers: ["1998", "2000", "2002", "1999"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Which of the following was not a launch game for the Dreamcast in the US?", answers: ["Hydro Thunder", "Jet Set Radio", "Soulcalibur", "Power Stone"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Who is the designer of Shenmue?", answers: ["Naoto Ohshima", "Yu Suzuki", "Hideaki Itsuno", "Masayoshi Kikuchi"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Which platform is Crazy Taxi not available on?", answers: ["Dreamcast", "PlayStation 2", "GameCube", "Saturn"], correct: 3}
    ]
  },
  {
    name: "Nintendo Trivia",
    uniqueID: "nintendo",
    colour: "#E60012",
    unlock: unlockNintendo,
    questions: [
      {question: "When was Nintendo founded?", answers: ["1981", "1889", "1893", "1942"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When was the NES released in Japan?", answers: ["1985", "1979", "1983", "1984"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Who was the producer of Metroid(1986)?", answers: ["Fusajiro Yamauchi", "Yoshio Sakamoto", "Satoru Iwata", "Gunpei Yokoi"], correct: 3},
      {question: "When was the SNES released in North America?", answers: ["1991", "1992", "1989", "1990"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Who succeeded Hiroshi Yamauchi as president of Nintendo?", answers: ["Fusajiro Yamauchi", "Shigeru Miyamoto", "Satoru Iwata", "Tsunekazu Ishihara"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When was Super Mario Bros. 3 released in North America?", answers: ["1989", "1988", "1991", "1990"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Who is the producer of Super Mario RPG?", answers: ["Kazuhiko Aoki", "Chihiro Fujioka", "Shigeru Miyamoto", "Gunpei Yokoi"], correct: 2},
      {question: "What is the Super Nintendo Entertainment System called in Japan?", answers: ["Super Famico", "Super Famicom", "Ultra Arigatou", "Super Comboy"], correct: 1},
      {question: "What did Star Fox make use of to have 3D graphics?", answers: ["Super FX", "Mode 6", "Blast Processing", "O74BY Core"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Who is the composer of The Legend of Zelda: A Link the Past?", answers: ["Kensuke Tanabe", "Shigeru Miyamoto", "Kenji Yamamoto", "Koji Kondo"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Who is the Space Pirate commander in Super Metroid?", answers: ["Ridley", "Sylux", "Mother Brain", "Samus"], correct: 0},
      {question: "When was the Virtual Boy released in North America?", answers: ["1993", "1998", "1994", "1995"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Which of the following was a launch game for the Nintendo 64?", answers: ["GoldenEye 007", "Pilotwings 64", "Star Fox 64", "F-Zero X"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When was Super Smash Bros. released in Europe?", answers:["2000", "1999", "1997", "2001"], correct: 1},
      {question: "How many rupees does the Deku Shield, in Ocarina of Time, cost?", answers: ["80", "40", "60", "50"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When did Gunpei Yokoi leave Nintendo?", answers: ["1994", "1999", "1997", "1996"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Who is the producer of Donkey Kong 64?", answers: ["David Wise", "Gregg Mayles", "Shigeru Miyamoto", "Taiki Ubukata"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When was the Game Boy Color released in North America?", answers: ["1998", "1989", "1994", "1996"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Which of the following was not a launch game for the Game Boy Color in the US?", answers: ["Centipede", "Tetris DX", "Pocket Bomberman", "Dr. Mario"], correct: 3},
      {question: "What was the codename for the Gamecube?", answers: ["Revolution", "Oxygen", "Dolphin", "Project Reality"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When was the Gamecube released in North America?", answers: ["2003", "2001", "2002", "2000"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Who is the composer of Star Fox Adventures?", answers: ["David Wise", "Shigeru Miyamoto", "Lee Schuneman", "Koji Kondo"], correct: 0},
      {question: "What was the codename for the Wii?", answers: ["Revolution", "Oxygen", "Dolphin", "Project Reality"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Which of the following was not a launch game for the Wii in the US?", answers: ["Twilight Princess", "Red Steel", "Need for Speed: Carbon", "Super Mario Galaxy"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Which of the following was not a launch game for the Wii U in the US?", answers: ["Pikmin 3", "Assassin's Creed III", "New Super Mario Bros. U", "Nintendo Land"], correct: 0}
    ]
  },
  {
    name: "SNK Trivia",
    uniqueID: "snk",
    colour: "#0097E0",
    unlock: unlockSNK,
    questions: [
      {question: "When was SNK founded?", answers: ["1960", "1978", "1948", "1982"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Who founded SNK?", answers: ["Bonne Jenet", "Eiji Kisaragi", "Eikichi Kawasaki", "Ralf Jones"], correct: 2},
      {question: "What type of game is Ozma Wars?", answers: ["Shooter", "Sports", "Racing", "RPG"], correct: 0},
      {question: "What does SNK stand for?", answers: ["Shin Nihon Kikaku", "Super Nintendo Kontender", "Saka Neko Kagi", "Shiro Naku Kori"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Which film series was Ikari Warriors inspired by?", answers: ["Street Hawk", "Airwolf", "Rambo", "Cobra"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When was Alpha Mission released in North America?", answers: ["1985", "1979", "1989", "1982"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Which system was Crystalis released on?", answers: ["GBA", "Genesis", "SNES", "NES"], correct: 3},
      {question: "When was the Neo Geo MVS released in Japan?", answers: ["1988", "1990", "1997", "1993"], correct: 1},
      {question: "What was the Neo Geo MVS designed for?", answers: ["Arcades", "Homes", "Businesses", "Tourists"], correct: 0},
      {question: "When was the Neo Geo AES released in North America?", answers: ["1992", "1987", "1989", "1991"], correct: 3},
      {question: "What system was NAM-1975 originally released on?", answers: ["Playstation", "Genesis", "Neo Geo", "NES"], correct: 2},
      {question: "What type of game is Magician Lord?", answers: ["RPG", "Platformer", "Strategy", "Shooter"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When was Samurai Shodown II released?", answers: ["1989", "1998", "1994", "2000"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Which seal did SNK put on some of its games?", answers: ["Power", "Dog Tag", "Elephant", "Ninja"], correct: 1},
      {question: "What was Fatal Fury's biggest competitor?", answers: ["Tekken 3", "Street Fighter 2", "Soulcalibur", "Primal Rage"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Which game does The King of Fighters '94 not include characters from?", answers: ["Fatal Fury", "Ikari Warriors", "Sengoku", "Art of Fighting"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Who is the antagonist in the first Metal Slug game?", answers: ["Rock Howard", "General Morden", "Captain Zard", "Kasumi Todoh"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When was the Neo Geo Pocket Color released in Europe?", answers: ["1993", "2001", "1991", "1999"], correct: 3},
      {question: "When did the original SNK Corporation  close?", answers: ["2001", "2003", "2004", "1999"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Which company acquired SNK's IP?", answers: ["Nintendo", "Sega", "Playmore", "Sony"], correct: 2}
    ]
  },
  {
    name: "SquareSoft Trivia",
    uniqueID: "square",
    colour: "#C00A24",
    unlock: unlockSquareSoft,
    questions: [
      {question: "When was Square founded?", answers: ["1960", "1978", "1948", "1982"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When did Square merge with Enix?", answers: ["2003", "2005", "2001", "1999"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Which game was Square's first game released?", answers: ["Thexder", "Apple Town Story", "Final Fantasy", "The Death Trap"], correct: 3},
      {question: "What was Square's first console game?", answers: ["Final Fantasy", "Thexder", "Rad Racer", "Secret of Mana"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When was Final Fantasy first released?", answers: ["1987", "1991", "1984", "1989"], correct: 0},
      {question: "When was Secret of Mana first released?", answers: ["1992", "1987", "1993", "1989"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When was Chrono Trigger first released?", answers: ["1992", "1995", "1996", "1993"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Who was the producer of Chrono Trigger?", answers: ["Akira Toriyama", "Ryuji Sasai", "Kazuhiko Aok", "Nobuo Uematsu"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Who was the composer on Final Fantasy VII?", answers: ["Nobuo Uematsu", "Shinji Hashimoto", "Yoshinori Kitase", "Junya Nakano"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Where does Vagrant Story take place?", answers: ["Midgar", "Chronopolis", "Ignas", "Valendia"], correct: 3},
      {question: "When was Super Mario RPG first released?", answers: ["1992", "1996", "1998", "1989"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Who was the producer of Parasite Eve?", answers: ["Taketoshi Nishimori", "Shinji Hashimoto", "Masaharu Iwata", "Hironobu Sakaguchi"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Who was the producer of Chocobo Racing?", answers: ["Keiji Inafune", "Masaharu Iwata", "Shinji Hashimoto", "Toshiyuki Itahana"], correct: 2},
      {question: "What system was Kingdom Hearts first released on?", answers: ["Gamecube", "PlayStation 2", "Xbox 360", "PlayStation 3"], correct: 1},
      {question: "What is the leveling system called in Final Fantasy X", answers: ["L2", "Spira Points", "Active Level System", "Sphere Grid"], correct: 3}
    ]
  },
  {
    name: "Capcom Trivia",
    uniqueID: "capcom",
    colour: "#0C4CA3",
    unlock: unlockCapcom,
    questions: [
      {question: "When was Capcom established?", answers: ["1965", "1978", "1981", "1983"], correct: 3},
      {question: "When was Street Fighter II: The World Warrior first released?", answers: ["1987", "1994", "1991", "1989"], correct: 2},
      {question: "What system was Monster Hunter 2 first released on?", answers: ["Nintendo 64", "PlayStation 2", "Xbox", "Dreamcast"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Who is the main antagonist of the original Mega Man series?", answers: ["Dr. Wily", "Zero", "Doctor Eggman", "Iris"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Who is the creator of Zero?", answers: ["Harumi Fujita", "Keiji Inafune", "Nobuo Uematsu", "Hideo Kojima"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Who was the producer of Resident Evil 2?", answers: ["Akira Yamaoka", "Hideki Kamiya", "Shinji Mikami", "Noboru Sugimura"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When was Breath of Fire IV first released?", answers: ["1999", "2003", "1998", "2000"], correct: 3},
      {question: "When was Capcom vs. SNK 2 released?", answers: ["2001", "2005", "2006", "2007"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Who was the composer of 1942?", answers: ["Jeffrey Howell", "Hideki Kamiya", "Ayako Mori", "Tokuro Fujiwara"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Who is the protagonist of Dead Rising 3?", answers: ["Nick Ramos", "Naru Omori", "Chuck Greene", "Frank West"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Who is the protagonist of Dino Crisis?", answers: ["Zero", "Regina", "Chris Redfield", "Cammy"], correct: 0},
      {question: "When was Ōkami first released?", answers: ["2004", "2006", "2008", "2005"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When was Resident Evil 4 first released?", answers: ["2004", "2006", "2008", "2005"], correct: 3},
      {question: "What system was The King of Dragons released on?", answers: ["Sega Saturn", "PlayStation 4", "Super Nintendo", "Neo Geo"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When was DuckTales 2 first released?", answers: ["1988", "1990", "1986", "1993"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Who is the protagonist of Super Ghouls n' Ghosts?", answers: ["John", "George", "Arthur", "Frank"], correct: 2},
      {question: "What system was Gargoyle's Quest released on?", answers: ["Game Boy", "PlayStation Portable", "Game Boy Advance", "Game Gear"], correct: 0},
      {question: "What are the abilities called in Viewtiful Joe?", answers: ["S-Points", "VFX Powers", "Super Abilities", "Mini Gauge"], correct: 1},
      {question: "Who was the director of Dragon's Dogma?", answers: ["Inon Zur", "Nobuyuki Matsushima", "Hideaki Itsuno", "Panta Rhei"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When was Final Fight 3 first released?", answers: ["2014", "1989", "1995", "1993"], correct: 2},
    ]
  },
  {
    name: "Konami Trivia",
    uniqueID: "konami",
    colour: "#990014",
    unlock: unlockKonami,
    questions: [
      {question: "When was Konami founded?", answers: ["1957", "1967", "1969", "1976"], correct: 2},
      {question: "When did Konami start exporting products to the US?", answers: ["1974", "1982", "1971", "1979"], correct: 3},
      {question: "When was Frogger released in Europe?", answers: ["1982", "1986", "1978", "1979"], correct: 0},
      {question: "When was Super Cobra released?", answers: ["1977", "1981", "1988", "1990"], correct: 1},
      {question: "What was Gradius named outside of Japan?", answers: ["Ikaruga", "Feud", "Super R-Type", "Nemesis"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Who are the main characters in Contra?", answers: ["Bill & Lance", "Joe & Don", "Frank & Marcus", "Eiji & Izumi"], correct: 0},
      {question: "How many levels are there in Super Castlevania IV?", answers: ["11", "20", "8", "14"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Who do you play as in Castlevania II?", answers: ["Leonard Wolf,", "Simon Belmont", "Dracula", "Gabriel Belmont"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When was Silent Hill 2 released?", answers: ["1999", "2003", "2001", "1998"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Who was the composer on Silent Hill", answers: ["Trent Reznor", "Akira Yamaoka", "David Lynch", "Motoaki Furukawa"], correct: 1},
      {question: "When was Gradius III released?", answers: ["2001", "1978", "1989", "1985"], correct: 2},
      {question: "Which series is a spinoff of Gradius?", answers: ["Salamander", "Sine Mora", "Darius", "Radiant Silvergun"], correct: 0},
      {question: "Who is the creator of Metal Gear?", answers: ["Kenyu Horiuchi", "Pierluigi Collina", "Gakuto Mikumo", "Hideo Kojima"], correct: 3},
      {question: "Who is the protagonist of Metal Gear Solid 2?", answers: ["Raiden", "Ocelot", "Snake", "Kazuhira Miller"], correct: 0},
      {question: "When was Metal Gear Solid 4 released?", answers: ["2006", "2008", "2010", "2011"], correct: 1}
    ]
  }
].reverse();